(719) 439-0955 | austin.l.scott75@outlook.com | https://www.austinscott75.com

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dedicated **Software Engineer** highly regarded for designing, developing, and delivering custom web apps and software solutions. Applies a Java and object-oriented tech stack to excel in numerous academic coursework projects with real-world transferability. Out-of-the-box thinker specializing in game development and cybersecurity. Known as an integral member of every workplace for flexibility and outstanding work ethic. Pursuing a B.S. in Computer Science and Systems Engineering from UW.

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

# University of Washington, Tacoma, Tacoma, WA

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science and Systems Engineer

Relevant Coursework: Matrix Algebra w/Applications, Physics, Python, Differential Equations, Java, Computer Science Principles, Programming Practicum, and Discrete Structures, Data Structures, Data Algorithms, Machine Organization, Computer Architecture, Computer Ethics, C Programming, Computational Worlds, Database & Design, Database & Design 2, Operating Systems, Mobile Applications

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Senior Class Project | UW | 2021

- Commended by Professor Christopher Marriot for providing de facto team leadership and mentorship that produced a high-quality video game (A+ grade) for the TCSS 491 senior class project.
- ♦ Personally designed 2 intricate levels, the CPU and player functionality.

#### Various Java Programs | UW | 2018-2021

Applied object-oriented programming, input-based (scanner) programming, and write/read file capabilities to create projects, including a Mozart music generator, interactive quiz bowl, car rental program, photo editor, bubble/shell sort, Huffman coding tree, and a file-sorting desktop app.

# Various Python Programs | UW | 2018

Applied object-oriented programming, input-based (scanner) programming, and write/read file capabilities to create projects, including a library check in / check out, and earthquake tracking applications.

## Various C Programs | UW | 2021

♦ Developed 5+ user interaction-based reading/writing files such as an interactive desktop app for homeowners.

#### Portfolio Website | UW | 2021

- ♦ Self-learned HTML, PHP, and CSS to create a fully-functional and elastic portfolio website.
- https://austinscott75.com

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Dock Associate 2019 - Present

#### FedEx Freight: Kent, WA

- Served as a certified forklift operator to load/unload freight trailers against rigorous schedule, safety, and quality requirements in a fast-paced, time management-intensive warehouse environment.
- ♦ Inputted freight information into the internal database and manage task queues.

# Warehouse Associate 2019 - Present

### Coastal Farm & Ranch: Auburn, WA

- ♦ Operated in a multi-faceted role as a certified propane dispenser, licensed forklift operator, propane and forklift operations crew trainer, and shipping/receiving load specialist (customer & commercial vehicles).
- Enforced 100% compliance with merchandise quality and customer service standards while offering live power equipment demonstrations to customers to facilitate sales.

## **TECHNOLOGY & TOOLS**

Microsoft Office Suite / Python / Java / HTML / C / CSS / JavaScript / SQL / Machine Learning / PHP

# **COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT**

Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation (JDRF): Annual fund-raising volunteer Kent Schools – Volunteer Judo Black Belt Coach

## **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

Software Engineering Gameplay Level Design Object-Oriented Programming Java, Python, C Agile Methodology

Data Structures

2021

Machine Learning
Time Management

Team Collaboration

Full-Stack Development

Front-End Technologies

Troubleshooting

Debugging

Mobile & Web Apps